# ABIODUN OLONADE

36 Transit village 2, Adetokunbo Ademola Street, Victoria island, Lagos state <u>emmanuel olonade@yahoo.com</u> | (+234)-80-3282-7281 / (+234)-70-1510-9571 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/abiodun-emmanuel

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Graduate of Electronics and Electrical Engineering with a major in Communication engineering. Highly organized and resourceful entry-level front-end developer with a superb work ethic, engineering and coding background. Seeking to leverage my 5+ years' programming skills as a Junior Software Engineer.

I am a passionate front-end web developer with 3years+ of learning experience using HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and React JS to build all aspects of the user experience and user interface for web apps.

# **SKILLS**

# **Database and Programming Languages**

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Modern JavaScript, React JS, Next JS, Redux, Material UI, Debugging, Git/GitHub

#### **Software Tools**

Microsoft Word, Excel and Power point.
WordPress.

# **Communication and Interpersonal**

Effective communicator Decision-maker and Problem solver Critical and Analytical Thinking Eager to learn

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Ladoke Akintola University of Technology** | Bachelor of Technology

*Ogbomoso, Oyo State* | **11.2015** – **12.2021** 

- Major in Electronics and Electrical Engineering
- Coursework: Communication Engineering
- Member of Nigeria society of engineers (Graduate member)
- Grade: Second Class Upper

# **Educational legacy college |** High School

*Ibadan, Oyo State* | **09.2007 – 08.2013** 

- Science Department
- West African Senior School Certificate Examination (WASSCE) certified
- National Examination Council (NECO) certified

# **PROJECTS**

#### **GitHub Repository**

https://github.com/SlimPapii

**Project: Responsive Website Design** 

Role: Developer

Technologies: HTML and CSS

Responsibilities: I designed and developed the <a href="https://transportservices.netlify.app">https://transportservices.netlify.app</a> using HTML and CSS only in order to showcase my understanding of responsive designs.

**Project: Login Page Authentication** 

Role: Developer

Technologies: HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Responsibilities: I designed and developed the <a href="https://loginpageauth.netlify.app/">https://loginpageauth.netlify.app/</a> using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. I made use of local storage to save the details of the user.

Project: Ode to Zainab - NonProfit

Role: Lead Developer

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React

Responsibilities: I designed and developed the https://ode-to-zainab.vercel.app/ using React JS also implemented

navigation using React Router.

More projects are available on my repository, link is above

#### RELATED EXPERIENCE

#### **BEESTECH** | Volunteer

Ibadan, Oyo State | 02.2020 - Present

- Created more than 5 web application with HTML and CSS3
- Used CSS media queries/Bootstrap to design multiple responsive web apps
- Created, maintained, and enforced front-end code and documentation standards (readable codes)

#### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### NoemDek Limited | IT/Procurement Analyst

*Ikoyi, Lagos* | **08.2022 – Present** 

- Determining supply needs and researching potential suppliers.
- Acting as a liaison and communicating pricing and performance needs to vendors and suppliers.
- Sourcing suppliers and testing product samples.
- Documenting the features and benefits of products and services.
- Preparing cost-benefit analysis reports for review by managers.
- Negotiating favorable procurement contracts with selected vendors and suppliers.
- Documenting processes and generating monthly supply cost reports.
- Monitoring the company's demand for products to avoid supply shortages.
- Keeping abreast of vendor and supplier-related activities in the industry.

#### **HUAWEI TECHNOLOGY.CO.NIG LTD** | INTERN

*Lekki-epe, Lagos* | **08.2020 – 12.2020** 

Airtel managed service telecommunication engineer

- Effectively & efficiently maintaining the BTS & Access Radio Network; ensuring the overall network
  availability meets the pre-set targets as laid out by the management, taking into cognizance the platinum,
  gold, silver & bronze sites are all placed in order of Priorities.
- Efficient resolution of all Network Faults (Power outages, Transmission Access Radio & BTS failures) ensuring that the average downtime of 6 hours for MTTR is maintained.
- Troubleshooting and configuration of Node B on both ATM and IP RAN link.
- Proffer solutions to repetitive BSS network problems affecting network quality and availability on all BSS Platform as assigned.
- Installation & Maintenance of the BTS and transmission equipment.
- Site configuration in accordance with Installation Specifications.

#### **SIR KAY Electrical works** | *INTERN*

*Ibadan,Oyo State* | **05.2016** – **01.2017** 

• Surface and conduit wiring

#### **INTERESTS**

Travel enthusiast with keen interest in other cultures, coding, meeting new faces, listening to Music and also I enjoy watching football matches.

#### **VOLUNTEERS**

I was a member of Transformation Academy group, where I take fresh year students Mathematics and I also take the year two students Engineering Analysis. This has helped me to build confidence to approach a large crowd and convince them to listen and buy into my ideas.

### **REFERENCES**

AVAILABLE ON REQUEST.